hey guys I love this problem it says the
width is twice the height if the
perimeter is 120 what is the area and
we're given that the width is x^2 - x -
16 and the height is x + 12 if you want
to try this on your own pause it right
now cuz I'm going to solve it in 3 2 1
there are two ways to solve this one I'm
going to show you both ways we'll do the
hard way first and then I'll show you
the shortcut so it says the width is
twice the height for the width I'm going
to plug in the x^2 - x - 16 and that's
going to be equal to 2 * the height
where the height is this x + 12 then we
can distribute this to it'll be 2x + 24
then since it's a quadratic let's set it
equal to 0 so we can subtract 2x from
both sides and subtract 24 from both
sides let's bring down the x^ 2x - 2x is
-3x and -6 - 24 is -40 and that will all
be equal to zero so we can Factor this
we need two numbers that add to -3 and
multiply to -40 that's going to be8 and
POS 58 + 5 is 3 and8 * 5 is -40 so we
can plug those in here now since this *
this is equal to 0 we know either this
equals 0 or this equals 0 which means
either x = 8 or x = 5 now let's test our
solution so let's take the x = 5 and
let's plug it in5 + 12 gives us 7 and
this will be 25 + 5 which is 30 - 16 is
14 the perimeter would be equal to 14 +
7 + 14 + 7 which is only 42 we need the
perimeter to be 1 20 and that does not
equal 42 so x = 5 is an extren solution
next let's try x = 8 so let's plug in 8
for all the X's we get 20 on the height
and 82 is 64 - 8 is 56 - 16 is 40 40 is
twice as big is 20 and for the perimeter
40 + 20 + 40 + 20 does give us 120 so x
= 8 is our solution and the question is
asking what is the area 40 * 20 is 800
and we can give it a label of unit
squared so that is the answer to our
question 800 unit squar so now would you
like to see the alternative method these
are a trap we don't need these so we can
just assign H for the height and call
the width 2 H because the width is twice
the height so we need the perimeter to
be 120 that means we need H + 2 H + H +
2 H to equal 120 and H + 2 h plus h + 2
H is equal to 6 h after we divide both
sides by 6 we get H equal to 20 so we
can plug in 20 for these H's and the two
h's will become 40 40 + 20 + 40 + 20
gives us 120 and then the area will be
40 * 20 which is 800 unit squared and
that's the answer to the question how
exciting so which method did you like
more